crabtree-evelyn.com 2018-06-02

# Privacy Policy

Last Updated: 12/16/2015

At Crabtree & Evelyn we understand and respect your concerns about the privacy and security of your personal information. We are committed to maintaining and using your information responsibly. We collect information for one reason - to help serve you better.

Please take a moment to read our Privacy Policy. It explains what types of information we collect, how that information is used, to whom it is disclosed, and how it is safeguarded. This Privacy Policy applies to all information previously or currently provided to or collected by us. By interacting with Crabtree & Evelyn, including using www.crabtree-evelyn.com (the "Site"), you consent to our use of your information as described in this Privacy Policy. We may change our Privacy Policy and when we do we will publish the changes here. For this reason, we encourage you to review our Privacy Policy periodically.

  * What information is collected?
  * Do you use cookies or pixel tags?
  * How is my information used?
  * Will my information be shared with third parties?
  * What choices do I have?
  * What about links to other websites?
  * How is my personal information protected?
  * Do you collect information from children?
  * How do you respond to Do Not Track signals?
  * Your California Privacy Rights.

#### What information is collected?

We collect personally identifiable information that you provide, such as your name, billing address, shipping address, telephone number, e-mail address, credit card information, and birth month, when you:

  * Make a purchase
  * Enroll in a loyalty, rewards, or promotional program
  * Participate in interactive features on the Site such as product reviews
  * Sign up to receive e-mails or other notifications from us
  * Enter a contest or sweepstakes
  * Fill out a survey
  * Create a Crabtree & Evelyn account
  * Use a social media service like Facebook or Twitter to communicate with us
  * Submit a request to our customer service department

#### Do you use cookies or pixel tags?

Like most websites, the Site employs various types of technology, including cookies and pixel tags, that receive and store information when you interact with the Site.

Cookies are small files that are stored by your browser on your computer when you visit a website. They enable you to shop on the Site and are used in a variety of ways to enhance or personalize your online browsing and shopping experience. For instance, we use cookies to remember what items are in your shopping cart, to recognize you when you return to the Site, to study how customers navigate the Site, and to deliver personalized marketing. Most Internet browsers are initially set to accept cookies. You can set your browser to refuse cookies from websites or to remove cookies from your hard drive but, if you do, you will not be able to access or use portions of the Site. Consult your browser's 'help' section for instructions on how to disable cookies. You can learn more about cookies at [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

Pixel tags (also called web beacons) are tiny graphic images on the Site and in our emails. They assist in delivering cookies and help us determine whether a specific action has been taken, like viewing a web page on the Site or opening an email.

We use third parties such as network advertisers and social media, including Facebook, to serve advertisements on third-party websites or other media (e.g., social networking platforms). This enables us and these third parties to target advertisements to you for products and services in which you might be interested. Third-party ad network providers, advertisers, sponsors and/or traffic measurement services may collect Non-PII Data and use cookies, JavaScript, web beacons (including clear GIFs), Flash LSOs and other tracking technologies to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content to you. These third-party cookies and other technologies are governed by each third party's specific privacy policy, not this one. We may provide these third-party advertisers with information, including personal information, about you to assist us with this advertising.

Users in the United States may opt out of many third-party ad networks, including those we work with on our Website and App. For example, you may go to the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”) [Consumer Choice Page](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) for information about opting out of interest-based advertising and their choices regarding having information used by [DAA companies](http://www.aboutads.info/participating/). You may also go to the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) [Consumer Opt-Out Page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) for information about opting out of interest-based advertising and their choices regarding having information used by[ NAI members](http://www.networkadvertising.org/participating-networks).

Opting out from one or more companies listed on the DAA Consumer Choice Page or the NAI Consumer Opt-Out Page will opt you out from those companies' delivery of interest-based content or ads to you, but it does not mean you will no longer receive any advertising through our Site or on other websites. You may continue to receive advertisements, for example, based on the particular website that you are viewing (i.e., contextually based ads). Also, if your browsers are configured to reject cookies when you opt out on the DAA or NAI websites, your opt out may not be effective. Additional information is available on the DAA's website at www.aboutads.info or the NAI's website at www.networkadvertising.org.

#### Disclosure as to Google Analytics Features

We have enabled and use on the Site applications available from Google, termed Google Analytics Advertising Features. These include: Remarketing with Google Analytics, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, and Google AdWords. These Advertising Features work together with cookies and cookie technology.

The Advertising Features collect specific visitor cookie data, such as the source, medium, and keyword used to visit the Site, and other information, such as how often users visit this Site, what pages they visit when they do so, and what other sites they used prior to coming to this Site. We use the information we get from Google Analytics only to improve this Site. Google Analytics collects only the IP address assigned to you on the date you visit this Site.

We use Remarketing with Google Analytics in conjunction with Google AdWords to display content specific advertisements to visitors that have previously visited our Site when those visitors go to other websites that have the Google Display Network implemented.

Although Google Analytics plants a permanent cookie on your web browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit this Site, the cookie cannot be used by anyone but Google. Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to this Site is restricted by the Google Analytics Terms of Use and the Google Privacy Policy. You can prevent Google Analytics from recognizing you on return visits to this site by disabling cookies on your browser. Or, to opt out of Google Advertising Features specifically, you can access Google Analytics' currently available opt-outs [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

#### How is my information used?

We may use the information we collect in the following ways:

  * To process, track, and fulfill your order
  * To communicate with you about the status of an order
  * To identify your product and service preferences
  * To administer a sweepstakes or contest
  * To deliver coupons, marketing communications, and ads
  * To administer loyalty, rewards, and promotional programs
  * To improve the effectiveness of the Site and our marketing efforts
  * To prevent fraudulent transactions

#### Will my information be shared with third parties?

Crabtree & Evelyn does not sell or rent any personal information about our customers to any third party. We do share information we collect from you within the Crabtree & Evelyn group of affiliated companies. We also may share your information with companies that provide support services to us (such as shipping, name, and address verification; customer service; contest administration; e-mail distribution; and promotions fulfillment) or that help us market our products and services. These companies are not authorized to use the information we share with them for any other purpose or to send you unsolicited mail. We may also share information that you elect to make available to the public on the Site or social media networks. For example, if you post a product review on the Site or interact with us on social media sites and elect to make it available to the public, your information will be accessible on the Site and our social applications. With your prior consent, we may share names and addresses from our mailing list with carefully chosen marketing partners. We may also share aggregated statistical or demographic information with third parties in a manner that does not reveal personally identifiable information.

#### What choices do I have?

If you would prefer not to receive our emails you may click here or follow the removal instructions at the bottom of the next email that you receive from crabtree-evelyn.com. Please note that if you make subsequent purchases from our website, we will confirm your order by email, and we may need to contact you by phone, email or postal mail with other questions regarding your order.

If you would like to update your customer information or ask a question you may contact us as follows:

By email: | [askus@crabtree-evelyn.com](mailto:askus@crabtree-evelyn.com)  
---|---  
By Phone: | 1-800-272-2873  
Fax: | 1-800-253-1519  
By Mail: | Customer Service Department  
102 Peake Brook Road  
Woodstock CT 06281  
  
If you wish to refuse or remove Crabtree & Evelyn cookies you should consult your browser's 'help' section for instructions. You can learn more about managing cookies at [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). Please note that if you block or remove our cookies portions of the Site will not function.

To understand your choices regarding third party cookies please visit [http://www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/).

#### What about links to other websites?

For your convenience, the Site may include links which will take you to other websites that are not under our control. These websites have their own privacy and security policies which you should review. Crabtree & Evelyn has no responsibility for linked websites.

#### How is my personal information protected?

We maintain administrative, technical, and physical safeguards to protect your information. Also, for your security, we do not store your credit card or debit card information.

#### Do you collect personal information from children?

Our Site is not directed at children and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13 without verifiable parental consent. If we learn that a child under the age of 13 has submitted personal information online without verifiable parental consent, we will take all reasonable measures to delete such information and to not use it for any purpose (except as necessary to protect the safety of the child or others as required or permitted by law). If you become aware of any personal information we have collected from children under 13, please contact us.

#### How do you respond to Do Not Track signals?

Do Not Track (DNT) is a privacy preference that users can set in some web browsers, allowing users to opt out of tracking by websites and online services. At the present time, the World Wide Web Consortium (W3C) has not yet established universal standards for recognizable DNT signals and therefore, we do not recognize DNT.

#### Your California Privacy Rights.

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits customers of Crabtree & Evelyn who are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please write to us at the following address:

Crabtree & Evelyn, Ltd.  
102 Peake Brooke Rd.  
Woodstock, CT 06281  
Attn: Office of General Counsel
